Contact

yuk.agr19@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ yagrawal-962113 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Core Java

Java

MS Project

Languages

Hindi (Professional Working)
English (Professional Working)
Sanskrit (Elementary)

Certifications

Cloudera Certified Hadoop Administrator

AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate

Cloudera Certified Hadoop Developer

Yukti Agrawal

AWS Certified Solutions Architect | GCP| Data Engineering consultant at Accenture ASEAN

Singapore

Summary

Experienced Administrative with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in Cloudera, Hortonworks, Oracle Database, Hive, yarn, kafka, ELK stack, Nifi and HBase. Strong administrative professional with a Bachelor's Degree focused in Electrical and Electronics Engineering from MITS Gwalior.

Experience

Accenture
Data Engineering consultant
February 2019 - Present (1 year 7 months)
Singapore

Crédit Agricole CIB Hadoop Support Analyst March 2018 - January 2019 (11 months) Singapore

Cognizant
Hadoop Admin
July 2016 - February 2018 (1 year 8 months)
Pune Area, India

Tata Consultancy Services
Hadoop Administrator/Developer
April 2013 - June 2016 (3 years 3 months)

Joined as a trainee where I completed my training in java and mysql. There after worked for a US based financial banking firm in which my responsibilities include designing and supporting the business processes based on clients requirement using a technology called MFT(Managed File Transfer). Next joined the project called NextGen Solutions which was responsible for providing internal Hadoop trainings to young associates and then prepare them to join project accounts which require Big Data Technologies and Java

to implement algorithms efficiently. Grown to be perceived as an expert at administering and monitoring the Hadoop cluster and good learning in Unix/Linux, JAVA environment and Big Data Open source technologies like Map-Reduce, PIG, Hive, Sqoop, Oozie Hue, Apache Kafka, MapR, HBase, MongoDB and Business Intelligence tool like Tableau.

The role that followed thereafter was that of a "Hadoop Administrator" for one of the biggest bank of UK. In this role, I had successfully completed the Production Cluster Set Up of 7 nodes using Cloudera Manager 4.8.0 (Enterprise Edition), and had updated the version to 5.0.1. and then to 5.1.0. Also analyzed the differences between RDBMS (Teradata) and Hadoop. I was successful in solving a number of problems faced while migrating data from Teradata to Hadoop. Got an opportunity to equip myself with conceptual and working knowledge on different Hadoop ecosystem component usages via HUE Web UI during that project.

The client had an urgent requirement for database in production mode with full security features. To achieve this, I had installed Kerberos along with Apache Sentry and integrated with their existing Active Directory (LDAP) server to provide authorization and role-based access control.

I was accountable to deliver customer Proof of Concepts and understanding customer business requirements. Recommended customers about technology selection to solve Big Data problems and exploring different tools related to Big Data.

Education

MITS Gwalior

Bachelor's Degree, Electrical and Electronics Engineering (2008 - 2012)

Miss Hill's Gwalior (2006 - 2008)